Huey, get some rest when you get to the hospital.
休伊 到醫院後 你也要休息一下喔
Thank you, madam.
謝謝夫人
A moving carnival?
移動嘉年華嗎
You've always wanted to see it, right? That's good.
你一直很想看對吧 太好了呢
My foot is injured like this. What's so good about it?
腳傷成這樣 有什麼好的
Excuse me.
不好意思
What's wrong?
咦 怎麼了
I need to check both of your luggage.
我要檢查一下兩位的行李
We're not allowed to bring chocolate?
難道是不能帶巧克力嗎
This way, please.
這邊請
It's right here.
就是這裡
Hello.
你好
It's you.
咦 是你啊
I see.
原來如此
Thank you for your hard work.
辛苦你了
Where's Viola's id?
拜歐拉的伊德呢
I take this.
確實沒錯
Sorry to bother you two.
抱歉打擾兩位了
Then enjoy the journey.
那麼 祝兩位旅途愉快
Thank you.
感恩
Is this that bird?
是那隻小鳥
It's Bird No. 2.
是小鳥二號機
Yes.
是
Yes, no problem.
是 可以
Yes, it's already done.
是 已經完成了
Yes.
是啊
Yes, I got it.
是的 我收到了
Not at all, thank you.
不會 非常感謝
Yes.
是
Thank you.
謝謝
That's it for now.
那就先這樣
Is it from Gene?
吉恩打來的嗎
You should call him Deputy Director Junghardt instead of Gene.
不是吉恩 妳要叫他容格哈特次長啦
Don't mix things up.
不可以公私不分
Well…
那個…
What did he say?
他怎麼說
What do you mean?
什麼怎麼說
I mean…
就是…
Didn't we do our job well?
工作不是執行得很順利嗎
So I wonder how he thinks of these matters.
所以不知道 他是如何看待這些事…之類的
Your brother is so looking forward to it.
妳哥哥他啊 很期待喔
Really?
真的嗎
Yes, he's really looking forward to my performance.
嗯 期待我的表現
He also said, "Please take care of Rouge in the future."
他還說"今後也請妳多多照顧露瓊"
What?
什麼
(Metallic Rouge)
《金屬口紅》
Nius.
紐斯
Achillus.
阿基里斯
Viola.
拜歐拉
Immortal Nine.
Immortal Nine
No.
不…
Now there are only six people left.
剩下6個人了
Deputy Director Junghardt.
容格哈特次長
Viola's id that we collected has left Mars.
接收到完成拜歐拉伊德的回收 並離開火星的報告
But
但是…
the Ochrona seems to be investigating it too.
守護局似乎也正在四處探查
Hmm.
嗯
If they find out, we will be in trouble.
被他們查到就麻煩了
I'll have the strategy ready.
我會先備好策略
And about that moving carnival.
還有就是關於那個移動嘉年華
It seems to be on the Mars that Miss Rouge is heading to.
似乎在露瓊小姐所前往的火星上…
It's going to be held in Wellstown, right?
不是要在威爾斯鎮舉辦嗎
Looks like it isn't an accident.
看來並非是一場偶然呢
About the next target,
關於下一個目標
the clues to Phantom Verde seem to be in the Nean Settlement.
"幻影的維杜"的線索 似乎就在涅安居留地裡
I think all the Immortal Nine could transform into humans, right?
不朽九人不是都能化身為人類嗎
Maybe there are also some who deliberately mix in the Neans.
或許也是有刻意以涅安之姿 混在涅安裡的人喔
That's Detective Ash from the Ochrona.
是守護局的亞許探員
It's hard work coming all the way to Mars.
大老遠跑來火星也真是辛苦他了
Is he from the Ochrona?
他是守護局的人嗎
Hmm.
嗯
I've seen him on the list.
我有在名單上看到過
I heard that he's a tough
聽說是個老練探員…
and insignificant detective.
的樣子
Nean.
涅安…
What is going on?
到底是怎麼回事
Of course.
這是當然的
After all, this city has the largest Nean Settlement on Mars.
畢竟這座城市 可是火星最大的涅安居留地
You must be happy to see them.
看到一堆同伴 想必一定很高興
Right?
沒錯吧
To enter the settlement, we must pass through a heavily guarded gate.
要進去居留地 就必須通過戒備森嚴的大門
Only registered Neans and associates can enter.
除了已登記的涅安與相關人士外 不得進入
What did Gene say?
吉恩怎麼說
He told us to do it ourselves.
交給我們
Oh my. He shouldn't just make the half schedule.
真是的 約會行程不要只安排到一半啊
Boiled crab legs are super delicious!
水煮蟹腳超好吃的啦
What?
咦
It's gone.
沒有…
My chocolate is gone.
我的巧克力不見了…
I remember there was more.
我記得還有的啊
Chocolate.
巧克力
Well, that…
啊 那個的話…
Here, this is for you.
來 這個給你們
Thank you.
謝謝…
Bye.
BYE BYE
Remember to brush your teeth.
要記得刷牙喔
Didn't you become an adult by sharing chocolate with those two kids?
妳不是成為 能將巧克力送給孩子的大人了嗎
You're really impressive.
好棒喔
I have to buy it.
我去買
No way.
不行
We'll discuss the battle plan next.
接下來要討論作戰計畫
Jill said I am free to go wherever I want.
吉兒說我可以自由行動
Jill?
吉兒
Why would you mention that person with the camera at a time like this?
為什麼會在這種時候 提到那個手拿相機的人
She said, "Freedom is the ability to make your own choices."
她說"自由就是能自己做出選擇"
Freedom?
自由
How could there be such a thing?
怎麼可能會有那種東西
Yes.
有
No.
沒有
You don't deserve to be an agent if you're free to act on your own.
隨自己的意思擅自行動的話 就沒資格做特務了
I have always fought with my own will.
一直以來 我都是以自己的意志在戰鬥
Naomi, aren't you just hiding and watching from behind?
直美不都只是躲在後面看而已嗎
The one who can't do anything without my support shouldn't say so.
少了我的支援就什麼也做不了的人 別在那裡大放厥詞
People like you are nothing but a tool of the Aletheia.
妳這種人 只不過是真理部的物品
You are just like a spare part.
算是備品般的存在
Hey.
喂…
She's gone.
走掉了
Naomi is an idiot.
直美是笨蛋…
Ah!
啊
Idiot.
笨蛋…
Hey, I think you just touched me.
喂 你剛剛摸到了吧
I didn't.
我沒有摸
Look, you did.
你看 摸到了
That's scary.
好可怕喔
I can't believe a Nean would touch humans without permission.
涅安居然會擅自觸摸人類
This guy must be broken.
這傢伙壞掉了吧
Broken.
壞掉了…
We have to get rid of things that are broken.
壞掉的物品就要處理掉才行呢
Wait.
請等一下
I didn't do anything.
我什麼也…
Shut up, Scar Head.
給我閉嘴 疤臉
I'll take you to the scrap yard.
我帶您去報廢場
What's wrong with you?
妳是怎樣
What are you looking at?
看什麼看
Hey.
喂
You!
妳這傢伙
Get down on the ground now.
馬上給我趴下
Nean is not a tool,
涅安不是物品
nor a spare part.
更不是備品
What are you talking about?
說什麼鬼話…
Leon, what's wrong?
里昂 怎麼了
Dr. Afdal.
阿夫戴爾醫生
Dr. Afdal, do you know each other?
阿夫戴爾醫生 你們認識嗎
He is my assistant.
他是我的助手
I see.
原來是這樣
Is that girl too?
那個女孩也是嗎
Well, yes.
呃…是啊
Alright then.
那好吧
Hey, let's head back.
喂 回去了
But…
咦 可是…
After all, we have been under the care of doctors.
畢竟一直承蒙醫生的關照
Please get me that stuff.
那個東西 要再麻煩您了
Hey, let's go.
喂 走了
Leon.
里昂
You should stay out of trouble.
別惹麻煩
I'm really sorry, Doctor.
非常抱歉 醫生
Let's go.
走吧
Yes.
是
Ah.
啊
Wait, well…
不是 就是…
Well…
那…那個
Do you want to go in there?
妳是想進去嗎
There's someone I'm looking for.
裡面有個我想找的人
I see.
這樣啊
Follow me.
跟我來
Doctor?
咦 醫生
Thank you.
辛苦了
It's Dr. Afdal.
原來是阿夫戴爾醫生
I object.
我反對
She could be from Alter.
她有可能是奧塔的人
It's too dangerous.
太危險了
No, she's definitely not…
不 她絕對不是…
Do not interrupt.
外來的涅安不要插嘴
Humans are looking for an opportunity to wipe us out.
人類正在尋找機會消滅我們
We don't need to meet some unknown Neans.
沒有必要去見那種來歷不明的涅安
No, let's meet her.
不 我們就見見她吧
Yubal.
猶巴
We need hope,
我們需要希望
even it's just a glimmer of hope.
即便那是條細如蛛絲的希望
Doctor.
醫生
Great.
太好了
What happened?
發生什麼事了嗎
Doctor, something's wrong.
醫生 不好了
Dahlia…
達莉亞她…
Hold her down.
快壓住她的身體
Yes.
是
You come and help too.
妳也過來幫忙
Hurry up.
別拖拖拉拉的
It's okay.
可以了
What?
咦
Dahlia.
達莉亞
Doctor.
醫生…
Thank you.
謝謝你
Dahlia has stabilized.
達莉亞她穩定下來了
Just for now.
只是暫時穩住罷了
Can't she be cured?
沒辦法治好嗎
Her signals are starting to lose sync.
她的信號變得無法同步
But if we let her die, her employer will be dissatisfied.
但要是讓她死了的話… 她的雇主會很囉嗦
Why?
為什麼
When hiring a Nean who fought in the war,
只要雇用參加戰爭回來的涅安
one can apply for subsidies.
就可以申請到輔助金
They don't even have the freedom to die.
就連求死的自由也沒有
I can't believe it.
好過分…
This place is kind of nice.
這裡還算是好的
The Neans deployed in the Venus Project
投入到金星計畫中的涅安
were oppressed by the humans in the harsh environment.
持續在那顆艱困行星上 被消耗殆盡
In that hellish world that humans had never had access to or seen,
在那個人類未曾接觸 未曾看見過的地獄世界裡
they worked until they died
為了將金星地球化而不斷工作
to terraform Venus.
直至死去
They're nothing but consumables.
根本就是消耗品
So where are you going now?
然後呢 妳又要去哪裡
I thought you are here to find someone.
我記得妳說過妳是要進來找人的
What?
咦
Well…
啊 那個…
Where am I supposed to look for him?
我該去哪裡找才好呢
What?
咦
He is cunning, and I don't know where he is.
他很狡猾 我也不知道他在哪裡
You're really funny.
妳還真是有意思
You are Miss Rouge, right?
妳是露瓊小姐對吧
I am Levy 328 from CFN.
我是CFN的雷比328
CF…
CF…
It's the Council of Free Nean.
是"涅安自由評議會"
Someone wants to meet you.
有人想要見妳一面
(Episode 3: Marginal City)
(3 境界之街)
What should I do? If this continues…
怎麼辦 再這樣下去的話…
Looks like things aren't going so well for you.
看來進展得不太順利呢
Director.
署長
About the investigation materials I asked you to help with…
關於我請您幫忙的那些搜查資料…
What?
咦
It's the case of the red figure.
就是那個紅色人影事件啊
He was spotted in Canal City the other day.
日前他也在運河市現身了
Sorry, I am quite busy.
不好意思 我現在很忙
Wait.
等…
I'm really sorry.
非常抱歉
Please leave.
請回吧
He is from the Ochrona. Is this okay?
他可是守護局的人 這樣沒關係嗎
Don't mind him.
別管他
Damn.
可惡…
No smoking here.
這棟建築物裡是禁煙的
Then what are they doing?
那他們在抽什麼
I'll go warn them.
我去警告他們
Hold on, don't.
等一下 不要啦
I went too far.
我說得太過火了…
I can't believe I said she is a tool and a spare part of the Aletheia.
居然說她是真理部的物品 備品…
I guess I'm not mature enough.
看來我還是不夠成熟呢
About the next target,
關於下一個目標
the clues to Phantom Verde seem to be in the Nean Settlement.
"幻影的維杜"的線索 似乎就在涅安居留地裡
Does she want to do it alone?
她該不會是想一個人…
No way.
不會的…
I suppose.
不會吧…
Huey.
休伊
It won't be wrong.
不會錯的
I saw that kid turned into that red figure.
我看見那個孩子變成那個紅色姿態
I see.
這樣啊
Nice to meet you, Rouge.
很高興認識妳 露瓊
My name is Yubal.
我叫做猶巴
Yes.
是…
Why would a member of the CFN look for a human?
CFN的成員 找一個人類會有什麼事呢
Who knows?
誰知道
Don't get involved with dangerous people.
你也別去跟危險的人混在一起
How could it be?
怎麼會危險呢
After all, we can't use violence.
畢竟我們無法使用暴力
CFN is just trying to fight for Nean's right to live freely.
CFN只是想為涅安爭取 能夠自由存活的權利而已
That's what everyone said at first.
一開始都是這麼說的
They just want to be alive and be free.
只是想要活著 只是想要自由
Gradually, they will find these are not enough to satisfy themselves.
漸漸地就會發現 這些滿足不了自已
In terms of greed, humans and Neans are the same.
在貪得無厭這一點 人類和涅安其實差不了多少
At least,
至少
humans are not sent to the battlefield since birth.
人類不會一出生就被送往戰場
All I know about the world
我對這個世界的認識
is the battlefield, this city and the factory.
就只有戰場 這座城市 和工廠三個地方
Duma.
仲馬
Dr. Afdal.
阿夫戴爾醫生
Long time no see.
好久不見了
We have ceased the fire with the Usurpers.
與篡奪者締結了停戰協定
This city exists for the Neans returning from the battlefield.
為了那些從戰場回來的涅安 而打造了這座城市
At first, humans allowed us to run this place on our own.
起初是允許我們自行管理這個地方
But now…
然而現在卻…
We are difficult in fighting for autonomy,
爭取自治權的行動窒礙難行
because of that wedge that's embedded in our consciousness,
全是因為 硬生生打在我們意識裡的楔子
that Asimov Code.
那個阿茲莫夫代碼
Do not harm humans.
不可加害於人類
Obey human orders.
要服從人類的命令
Must protect oneself.
必須要保護自己
My third parents were an elderly human couple,
我的第三任父母 是一對年長人類夫婦
who were nice.
是對很溫柔的夫妻
I am a Substitute Nean who was created for those childless humans.
為了膝下無子的人類 而製造出來的代替用涅安
I've had 23 human parents.
我有過23個人類父母
Some humans would treat cruelly to these Yubals, who look like children and won't grow up.
也曾經有人殘酷地對待 一直是兒童外表 不會長大的猶巴
I've said it.
我不是說過了嗎
Some humans are nice.
也有些人類是好人的
We just want to be free to live.
我們只不過是想要自由地活著罷了
Free?
自由
Alter.
奧塔
They are a Nean organization that uses force against humans.
他們是用武力反抗人類的涅安組織
Such people do exist.
這樣的人也確實存在
They've made contact with us too.
他們也有來和我們接觸過了
Even if they have the Asimov Code in them?
即便體內有阿茲莫夫代碼嗎
I don't know the details.
詳情我並不清楚
They could be the people I'm looking for.
他們說不定就是我在追查的人
You said they made contact with you?
你說他們有來跟你們接觸過
Looks like they have an agent on this settlement.
看來在這個居留地裡 似乎有他們的內應
Do you know who that is?
你知道那個內應是誰嗎
Do you have any clues?
你有頭緒嗎
I can't confirm.
我沒有證據能夠證實
But he is…
但他是…
What we're after
我們所追求的
is not your power,
並不是妳身上的力量
but the free will.
而是那自由的意志
The ability to interact with humans equally, without being bound by the Asimov Code.
可以不受阿茲莫夫代碼束縛 與人類平等來往
Your existence has a special meaning.
妳的存在就是其意義
The fact that there are Neans like you
光是知道有妳這樣的涅安存在
who are willing to move forward with us
並且願意和我們一同前進
can bring hopes to many Neans.
就能給眾多的涅安帶來希望
Hopes to Neans?
涅安的…希望
Of course, you don't have to give me an answer now.
當然 妳不用急著給我答覆
During your stay here, you can think it over.
待在這裡的這段時間裡 妳可以慢慢思考
Dr. Afdal,
那麼 阿夫戴爾醫生
I'll leave it to you then.
那就拜託你了
This guy is still not serious.
這傢伙還是一樣不正經
Doctor.
醫生
D-Dahlia…
達…達莉亞她
She must be grateful to you.
她應該很感謝醫生
The battlefield, this city, and the factory.
戰場和這座城市與工廠
She once said that these were the only places she knew about the world.
她曾說過她對世界的認識 就只有這三個地方
I only know this city.
我只認識這座城市
I've lived here since I was made.
打從被製造出來 就一直生活在這裡
I've been working as your assistant.
一直在當醫生的助手
If I could learn some skills from you and go help my fellows…
要是能在醫生的門下學習技術 進而去幫助同伴的話…
Didn't I tell you?
我不是說過了嗎
That's what everyone said at first.
一開始大家都是這樣說的
But…
但是…
Gradually, they'd become hard to satisfy.
漸漸地就會無法滿足
Doctor.
醫生…
Tool.
物品…
Spare part.
備品
Freedom.
自由
Hope.
希望…
If it was Naomi,
如果是直美的話…
what would she say?
她會怎麼說呢
Well…
那個…
Yubal is looking for you.
猶巴在找妳
Bingo!
找到了
She found her own way into the settlement.
她自己想辦法進去居留地了
She's quite capable.
看不出來滿有一套的嘛
He wanted to invite you in alone.
他說請妳一個人進去
Thank you.
謝謝你
What are you doing?
妳在搞什麼啦
I didn't do this.
不是我做的
I know.
我知道啦
And who is he?
然後呢 他是哪位
Yubal.
猶巴
Yubal 087.
猶巴087
He's a big shot.
呃…是大人物耶
Yubal.
猶巴
Did you…
難不成是妳把他…
Please calm down.
各位先冷靜
Let's keep a low profile for now.
暫時先把這件事壓下來吧
But…
但是…
If the humans find out,
要是被人類陣營知道的話
I'm sure they'll step in.
他們肯定會加以介入的
Well…
這…
Doctor, what's wrong?
醫生 有什麼事嗎
Director.
署長
What's the matter now?
現在是什麼狀況
We're going to the settlement to keep the peace.
要出發去居留地維持治安
What happened?
發生什麼事了
Whether you're from the Ochrona or other organizations, this is our jurisdiction.
不管你是守護局還是哪個單位 這裡是我們的管轄
Please stay out of our business.
還請你不要多管閒事
Aren't we all public servants?
我們不都是人民公僕嗎
Excuse me.
失陪了
Are you being set up by someone from Alter?
難道是被奧塔的人陷害了嗎
What should we do now?
這下怎麼辦